NDEGE ALBERT MUNENE

Software Engineer

Email: albertndege2@gmail.com

Portfolio: https://ndegealbert.vercel.app/

GitHub: https://github.com/ndegealbert

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ndege-albert-136178155/

Twitter: https://twitter.com/home?lang=en

Phone Number: 0727596412

I am a full stack developer who is strongest on frontend development, I have more than 4 years of experience as a software developer, my experience has allowed me to acquire solid knowledge in software Engineering.

Working with multiple teams has made me programming language agnostic, whichever language is used, I can quickly learn and practice the best development Practices. I find joy in learning new things every day and solving real problems.

As a person I am vibrant, energetic and passionate about what I do, I have been appreciated for being committed to the quality of product and for always wanting to know "why"

EXPERIENCE

iPay Africa_- Fintech Company

Role: Software Engineer

JUNE 2021 - PRESENT

- Improving various legacy services efficiency and stability by introducing multi-threading and asynchronous processing
- Development, testing and documentation of APIs.
- Research on new fit for future technologies and active implementation. Design and implementation
 of microservice architectures
- Implemented the company's payment gateway A platform that processed various payments such as merchant, utility and card payments, utilized different payment gateway to archive this .ie Mpesa Api ,Cellulant Api , Pesalink Api , Visa/Muster card , Mvisa, Amex and UnionPay

Technologies used:

- PHP Slim Framework
- JAVA Spring boot Framework
- JavaScript/Typescript React/Next.js

KEY ARCHIVEMENT:

- Acquired experience working in a fintech industry
- Maintained maximum uninterrupted flow of business-critical

Ada Labs Africa - Global Lab that host Startups Company in Africa

Role: Front-end Software Engineer

JAN 2021 – JUNE 2021

- Worked as a remote software developer of Agri-tech Startup based at Tanzania in developing and deploying Phemarket, a Market place for connecting farmers to Sell their Product
- Built innovative microservices (REST-API) using Node.js
- Built a Single page interactive web application using React, redux and styled-component
- Worked closely with other developers, UX designers, and systems analysts to deliver the product

Technologies used:

• JavaScript/Typescript – React and Redux

KEY ARCHIVEMENT:

Maintained maximum uninterrupted flow of business-critical

SMART BEAVER INNOVATION – Innovation Hub Company

Role: Front-end Software Engineer

MAY 2020 - FEB 2021

- Engineered modern applications (Smart beaver innovation management system) with PHP (Laravel), JavaScript (React), MySQL, and No SQL.
- Built innovative microservices (REST-API).
- Supported multiple teams, empowering them to do more through code reviews, and automated code quality checks.

Technologies used:

- PHP Laravel
- JavaScript/TypeScript React
- Database MySQL and Mongo Db

Key achievement:

Maintained maximum uninterrupted flow of business-critical

JKUAT INDUSTRIAL PARK— Laptop/Tablet Assembling Company

Role: Computer TECHNICIAN

MAY 2019 - SEP 2019

- Assembling and Configuring Tablet for 2019 census
- Installing firewalls and Testing census Devices
- · Setting up server for Census data

Key achievement: Identified and dealt with a significant process of Assembling Tablets and Laptops

Education

Bachelor of Information Technology

Jomo Kenyatta university of Agriculture and Technology

May 2016- Feb 2020

- Heavy focus on full stack engineering with modules on both front and backend processes.
- Built a mock payment system for an Android ecommerce app for a senior year project.
- Built Learning projects which can be found on my portfolio/GitHub

Skills:

Programming languages

- JavaScript (ES6) /TypeScript
- Php
- Java
- · Go lang currently learning

Databases:

- MySQL
- PostgreSQL
- Mongo DB

Libraries and framework:

- React.js & React-native
- Next.js
- Redux
- Laravel
- Spring-boot

Design and prototyping tool:

• Figma

Certification:

• AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

ENGINEERING SKILLS: Data Pipelines, Data structures and Algorithms, Testing and debugging, Data Scraping.

References

George Nduati Mwangi

Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology

Lecturer

0722610473

nduatigm@gmail.com

Tools & platform:

- Git & GitHub
- Docker
- Webpack
- Netlify
- Linux

Cloud Platform:

Amazon Web Service

EC2, RDS, IAM, S3, DynamoDB

Fred Ochieng

JKUAT industrial Park

Supervisor

0728289834

fredochiengokeyo@gmail.com